let's take a moment to check if we
understand how write-update coherence
works
suppose that the core has a single block
cache with a valid bit a tag and the
data and suppose that we have for such
cores numbered 0 1 2 & 3
suppose that core 0 reads from 700 first
so now it gets the valid bit to be 1 the
tag is 700 and let's say that the data
trees is 6
after this core 1 reads the same
location then Core 2 writes a value of
17 into this location and finally core
tree reads from that location after all
this in core 0 what is the valid bit in
the cache the tag is still 700 and what
is the data that we get and the same
four cores one two and three
what is the valid bit in each of these
caches and what's the data value placed
here you can use this as an example
where the valid bit is either 1 or 0 and
the data value in this case is 6
after this read so what's going on in
these 4 caches after we do this sequence
we complete this then this then this
then this